Hello everyone, welcome back to this another tutorial topic. So, to this topic for MongoDB,
query operators using the MongoDB shell, okay. So, in this session, I'll just try
perfect let's explore how to perform the advanced queries in the MongoDB using the various
query operations and the syntax, okay. So, now just go for the first example. So, first of all,
I have perfectly entered the connected MongoDB shell. So, I can just use the shell and
use for my collection to do, okay. So, now here first of all, use the dollar sign creation
operator to find a broken name, see the extract for the match, okay. So, here first of all,
I can just type the first comment, use the DB dot, use the collections name, the students,
okay. Now, here we can apply for the defined function and first of all, create this and this also
the curly brackets. So, in this insert defined for create again for this and then use for the
dollar sign, okay. And now create the cause and define for this thing. So, this common data
document for the collection or the edges equal to 30, okay. So, now here first into and you
can see here simply just create perfectly not error, okay. So, this executing this query
between the document or the edges field that are, okay. So, you can see here this query for the,
we can share the edge expect for 30 is table and secondly here, simply for one table is perfectly
defined for the extract for the edge of 30 for this first table, okay. So, you can understand.
So, next step here I can go for another example. So, dollar sign, the gd operator,
define the value greater than, okay. So, now here I can just simply type for the DB dot, use the
students, okay. So, the just I can ensure first of all here is in going for this document inside
there the zero and now I'm going to students. So, we can use the students inside create the whole
table, okay. So, now here first of all we are going to use means dot here I can install find function
and also create this kind of parenthesis and also this, okay. So, first of all I can define
for the edges long and type for again this kind of curly brackets and use the dollar sign for
the gd, okay. And we use for edges 25. So, define is perfectly and now here I can create for this
enter and you can see here perfectly see the result for greater than 25, 48 and 40 greater than,
you can see here perfectly the result and here the MongoDB executing this query,
return the document while the edge is greater than 25, okay. So, here perfectly created and now
here today is the next example. So, now you see the operator to find the document with the value
is specified, jk, okay. So, now I can just go. So, first of all here I can just copy for this,
okay. So, now I can just save the time. So, copy and paste for here, okay. So, now I can just type
for define for this on curly brackets. So, in the inside I can define for the share, okay.
And use for again the curly brackets and type for here the dollar sign use the key operator,
okay. And now here I can give the square brackets. So, square bracket inside I can create for the
new view, okay. And also here I can create for also here I can find this new name,
the loss for angels, okay. So, here use the Yes. So, the loss angelist and here the computer statement
put the name or the city did not add the new all the loss angelist. So, perfectly and now here
press central and you can see here perfectly working this statement and you can see here is the
age 25 name is allies and city loss angelist and the age 25 and perfectly say this, okay.
And I hope you for a plan to understand this session on here I have completely used this
data query operator. So, perfectly understand and completely done and I have perfectly used this
and MongoDB operator using for table information with the MongoDB shell, okay. And perfectly
understand decision. So, thank you for watching and happy coding, ok.